## MIHIR SONTAKE

Address: Apartment 12, Heather House, Cappavilla Village, University of Limerick, Limerick – V94 KTX3 <a href="https://linkedin.com/in/mihir-sontake">https://linkedin.com/in/mihir-sontake</a> | +353 (89) 202 6305 | <a href="mailto:sontakemihir@gmail.com">sontakemihir@gmail.com</a> | <a href="https://github.com/mihson95">https://github.com/mihson95</a>

## **PROFILE**

Proven software professional with diverse experience as a Graduate Teaching Assistant and ICT Tutor, enhancing course efficiency and delivering targeted Java sessions. As a Senior Software Developer at Rosmerta Technologies, led the migration to microservices, achieved a 67% latency reduction, and demonstrated technical proficiency in REST APIs in Spring Boot and Spring Cloud Gateway. At Citigroup, contributed to FX Local Markets projects, increasing test coverage by 3%. Recognized for resolving critical bugs during a Summer Internship, reducing resolution time by 94.45%. Evidence of a blend of technical expertise, collaborative problem-solving, and a commitment to achieving measurable results in dynamic environments.

## **SKILLS**

- Java 11, 8 | Spring Boot | Git | GitHub | JavaScript | Angular | TDD | OOP | TeamCity
- JUnit | Mockito | Postman | SQL | PostgreSQL | MySQL | DBeaver
- Microservices | SOLID | Design Patterns | Backend | Fullstack | Code Coverage
- Presentation Skills | Leadership | Teamwork | Collaboration
- Python | Machine Learning

## **EXPERIENCE**

09/2023 – 12/2023 Graduate Teaching Assistant, University of Limerick – Limerick, Ireland (On-Site)

• Worked as a Graduate Teaching Assistant for the BSc/MSc Immersive Software Engineering course

09/2023 – 12/2023 ICT Tutor, ICT Learning Centre, University of Limerick – Limerick, Ireland (On-Site)

- Worked as a drop-in tutor guiding students of Computer Science in Java, C, C++, SQL, and Web
- Worked as a Lab Assistant for Pair Programming in Java Course
- Delivered targeted Java sessions to 1st year undergrad Computer Science students

01/2022 – 08/2023 Senior Software Developer, Rosmerta Technologies Ltd. – Gurugram, India (Remote)

- Collaborated on the timely resolution of bugs for the Vehicle Tracking Solutions Team
- Developed API Gateway using Spring Cloud Gateway and achieved a 67% lowering in latency
- Modified REST APIs for presenting data for reports in a paginated way
- Created REST API for sending Multiple emails from the same Microsoft Outlook Account
- Optimised code to achieve a 50% latency improvement for REST APIs running big database queries

07/2017 – 06/2020 Technology Analyst, Citigroup – Pune, India (On-Site)

- Hired as part of the competitive Citi Analysts Program for Graduates in the ICG Business of Citigroup
- Contributed to the FX Local Markets Division Projects SONAR Dashboard and QFXLM
- Trained on TDD, Spring Framework, Java 8, OOP, and Working Financial Knowledge
- Increased the test coverage by 3% covering 8000 Lines of Code

05/2016 – 07/2016 Summer Intern, Citigroup – Chennai, India (On-Site)

- Resolved a critical bug of the E-Dealer FX Trading Platform of Citigroup
- Developed a Highly Efficient Solution by creating a web application interface
- Reduced the bug resolution time by 94.45%, from 2 hours to 10 minutes
- Recognised for benefits delivered to the business and awarded an offer based on performance

# **EDUCATION**

Graduating 09/2024 MSc Software Engineering with Data Analytics, University of Limerick – Limerick, Ireland

- QCV: 3.64/4 (Semester 1)
- Core Modules: (Semester 1) Software Design, Software Development Paradigms, Concurrency and Parallelism in Software Development, Machine Learning and Applications, Research Methods

07/2013 - 07/2017 Bachelor of Technology, Indian Institute of Technology Madras - Chennai, India

- GPA: 8.0/10.0
- Core Modules: Computational Engineering, Linear Algebra
- Elective Modules: Programming, Data Structures and Algorithms, Biological Data Analytics, Applied Statistics, Transportation Network Analysis

# **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Awarded the Faculty of Science and Engineering merit-based International Postgraduate Scholarship
- Attained an All India Rank 3245 in Joint Engineering Entrance Advanced 2013, being among the top 0.3 % out of 1 million candidates
- Received the Kishore Vaigyanik Protsahan Yojana Scholarship Award in High School, among the top 1000 students in India, for demonstrating exceptional aptitude in Science and Mathematics